<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Garys Docs – Development environment</title>
    <link>/docs/development-environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development environment on Garys Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 09:58:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/docs/development-environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Linux</title>
      <link>/docs/development-environment/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 09:59:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/development-environment/linux/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This computer is a general use computer, not a server. The basic install may be either the full Ubuntu desktop or my preference which is Lubuntu. Lubuntu is a lightweight version of Ubuntu, with a toned down graphical interface and no default installation of certain desktop software like an office suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not use the Ubuntu system as my primary computer but specifically for development and running of machine learning tasks. The machine learning tasks often take a lot of processing power and time, so expect the machine to be unavailable during those task runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main office computer is a Windows based machine. I often use Ubuntu in a headless configuration, so connectivity is important.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;

During installation of Ubuntu, make certain you are able to connect using wifi. Wifi often uses proprietary drivers that must be installed while connected to the internet.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, the version control system. Use It!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Git, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install git-all&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the version, &lt;code&gt;git --version&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure git,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git config --global user.name &amp;#34;Your Name&amp;#34;
git config --global user.email &amp;#34;youremail@domain.com&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;For help on &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/doc&#34;&gt;using git&lt;/a&gt;, see my &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/tips-and-tricks/#git&#34;&gt;Tips and tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Windows</title>
      <link>/docs/development-environment/windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 09:59:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/development-environment/windows/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This computer has been up and running for some time. I intend on documenting new applications that I add for development but also to back-document features and applications I use regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connecting-to-a-remote-server&#34;&gt;Connecting to a remote server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;putty-for-remote-connection&#34;&gt;PuTTY for remote connection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/&#34;&gt;PuTTy&lt;/a&gt; has been around for a long time and still works wonderfully and is regularly maintained. PuTTY is used by Windows machines to connect to OpenSSH servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I will only document actions needed to connect to a new Linux development server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;generate-a-key-pair&#34;&gt;Generate a key pair&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating a key pair and securely connecting to a remote Linux machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start &lt;strong&gt;PuTTYgen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the &lt;em&gt;Number of bits in a generated key&lt;/em&gt; to 2048.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Generate&lt;/strong&gt; to generate a new key pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a password to the &lt;em&gt;Key passphrase&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Confirm passphrase&lt;/em&gt;. If you choose to not have a password, then do not enter these here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save your public and private keys. The private key should not be shared but the public key may be freely shared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the target Linux computer,
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir ~/.ssh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nano ~/.ssh/authorized_keys&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the public key from the Windows PuTTYgen box and paste it into the authorized_keys file on your target. Save the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close PuTTYgen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open PuTTY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save a new session named &lt;em&gt;target&lt;/em&gt; and put &lt;em&gt;ip_address&lt;/em&gt; in the Host Name box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the configuration Category pane, select &lt;strong&gt;Connection &amp;gt; SSH &amp;gt; Auth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse to select the private key you created earlier for authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test by clicking Open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be required to enter in the username to log in with and also the password used to protect the key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Do not lose your private keys. Once the next configuration steps are complete, your private key and password are required to login remotely.&lt;/strong&gt; You will still be able to login from the console or with a keyboard and monitor.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tigervnc-for-remote-desktop&#34;&gt;TigerVNC for remote desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TigerVNC is used to connect to a desktop on a remote Linux server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;install-tigervnc-and-connect&#34;&gt;Install TigerVNC and connect&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TigerVNC/tigervnc/releases&#34;&gt;vncviewer binary for Windows&lt;/a&gt;. The name of the file is likely &lt;em&gt;vncviewer-ver.exe&lt;/em&gt;. Download the file to a location of your choice (I use C:\bin). Create a shortcut on the desktop and click to start the viewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tigervnc.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;TigerVNC viewer on Windows&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;TigerVNC viewer on Windows&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the above figure. In the &lt;em&gt;VNC server&lt;/em&gt; box enter the ip address of the server to connect to follwed by &lt;em&gt;:1&lt;/em&gt;, where 1 is the number of the desktop you started on the server. Click &lt;strong&gt;Connect&lt;/strong&gt; and enter your password when requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cannot-connect&#34;&gt;Cannot connect?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are having trouble connecting, check the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make certain that Xtigervnc is listening on the 0.0.0.0:590x interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that you entered the correct ip address and port number into the vncviewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check your firewalls.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Windows, temporarily turn off the firewall and try to connect again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Linux, &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw status&lt;/code&gt; shows if the fire wall is active. If it is, temporarily disable it using &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw disable&lt;/code&gt; and try to connect again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the problem is a firewall, correct the issue and move on. Firewalls are not yet part of this documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;connecting-to-jupyterhub&#34;&gt;Connecting to JupyterHub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply point your browser to the ip address of your server and append the port being served. The default port for JupyterHub is 8000, my &lt;a href=&#34;http://192.168.1.67:8000&#34;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-development-environment&#34;&gt;Windows development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these tools are already installed and working. Also, they are mostly simple and direct Windows installations. I will not be giving details on installation unless there is something unusual about the install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-windows-tools&#34;&gt;My Windows tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anaconda 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MatLab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TexMaker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
