<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Werk Space – Reviews</title>
    <link>/blog/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Werk Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/blog/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Gulf</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/05/22/gulf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 16:40:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/05/22/gulf/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-gulf-the-making-of-an-american-sea&#34;&gt;The Gulf: The Making of an American Sea&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Jack E. Davis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Stars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-fiction work about the Gulf of Mexico and the US states bordering it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-review&#34;&gt;My Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excellent book that covers the physical, social, and economic history of this area. I learned many things about which I had no knowledge of. The book does have an environmental slant and you will learn much about the exploitive nature of humanity. The author is a Professor of Environmental History.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is in four parts. Part 1 cover&amp;rsquo;s the prehistory and the introduction of Europeans into the area. the Gulf is clearly an area of abundance that is not initially appreciated by the Europeans. Part 2 takes place mostly in the 19th Century when extensive exploitation of its natural resources begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 3 takes us into the birth of the oil industry in the Gulf states and then its movement into the Gulf itself. The economic benefits of the oil industry are covered but the environmental effects are documented and highlighted. Part 4 covers the post-1943 period with extensive discussion of the development in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach of the book is to try to humanize the topic by focusing in on specific areas, stories, or persons and then to generalize. Sometimes this approach works very well but others it seems poorly constructed. A positive example is the coverage of the impact of the oil industry by discussion of the artist Walter Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has influenced my understanding on the exploitive nature of humanity. As a remembrance I purchased a water-colored print by Anderson. &lt;a href=&#34;https://walterandersonart.com/&#34;&gt;Realizations&lt;/a&gt; is a small shop run by the family of Walter Anderson, dedicated to making his artwork accessible to more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended. It will take some time to read and topics are sometimes very in-depth.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 410px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/blog/2022/05/22/gulf/terns_hu85530e071e30b3b46c85caff45af6fa9_682350_400x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;1022&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
Terns
&lt;small class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Blockprint: Walter Anderson and Watercolor: Elizabeth Huffmaster&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Three Body Problem</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/05/22/three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:03:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/05/22/three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-three-body-problem&#34;&gt;The Three Body Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Liu Cixin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Stars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a science fiction novel by a Chinese author that has won a number of awards. It is a very good science fiction story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-review&#34;&gt;My Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely enjoy the changed perspective of the Chinese author. It gave the story a very different feel, yet still connected to humanity. There is background story which starts during the Cultural Revolution. The main characters are scientific intellectuals, usually in the field of physics, and often professors. so the language used is somewhat technical but usually not too much to distract from the flow of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought the story in the first half to three fourths of the book was excellent. The setup of the main characters was well done. The use of the virtual reality video game was appropriate and engaging. It was shortly after Wang is brought into the ETO that the story seems to not know where to go and becomes much more generic. This is when the story directly confronts the ongoing role of the alien civilization invasion plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I found the concept of unfolding dimensions to be interesting but that the implementation in the sophons to be a bit ludicrous. I also thought the book did a poor job of explaining the motivations of those involved in the ETO, though a valiant attempt was made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Three Body Problem&lt;/em&gt; is definitely a book to read, especially for those who like science fiction. I used to be a big fan of this genre but have found it a struggle to read for the past 30 years. This book was not a struggle, in fact it is well written and puts forth some interesting ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Handmaids Tale</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/05/22/handmaids-tale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:03:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/05/22/handmaids-tale/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-handmaids-tale&#34;&gt;The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by Margaret Atwood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Stars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a dystopian fiction novel that has a Netflix series derived from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-review&#34;&gt;My Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the sort of book I would normally seek out but this and The Three Body Problem were recommended to me &amp;hellip; so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of the The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale is not a fun world in which to live. The author does an excellent job in conveying the tone of monotony and oppression. A well written novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are welcomed to the US after a hostile coup by an extreme fundamentalist Christian group that institutes a rule of, by, and for, elite males. Women are subjugated and all must be watchful for the secret police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel is written as a series of extracts as if from a diary. This is a style that I like very much. It provides personal insight but limited worldview which is very appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colors assignments and daily structure are thoughtfully written. I do hope that humanity would not so easily succumb to this sort of a takeover and fear that I would not live in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, read the &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale&lt;/em&gt; and let&amp;rsquo;s make certain that we remain an enlightened populace.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
