<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Garys Docs – News</title>
    <link>/blog/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Garys Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/blog/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: After Math</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/05/22/after-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 11:42:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/05/22/after-math/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;I started my MS in Mathematics at UWM in Fall of 2020. The intent was to improve my skills to become better at machine learning and AI. My mother passed away in Jan 2021 from COVID and I needed to take some time off from studies to fulfill all of my duties to family, etc. This meant I took an incomplete in the second semesters of Algebra and in Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to cover these in the following Fall and Spring semesters. In the Fall, the plan proceeded except for one problem. Topology was taking much more study time than expected and I was not able to cover an incomplete. Rather than continue this process I decided that I would not complete my MS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were options to extend my time studying for the MS but this does not fit with my plans for working on machine learning and ai. I am now comfortable with working with theory and proofs in Mathematics and will extend and continue non-formal studies as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyways!&lt;/strong&gt; Back to documenting my work and actively updating this site.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Starting my documentation site</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/04/16/starting-my-documentation-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 16:02:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/04/16/starting-my-documentation-site/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;During this crazy time of corona virus quarantine, I figured it is time to get some things done. One of those is updating my documentation efforts. I was last using a system based upon asciidoc, pandoc, and git, with some work done in markdown and hugo. It worked fairly well but was cumbersome in many regards. I last reviewed methods in 2018, which was prior to my restarting school in Mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this new site uses markdown instead of asciidoc. There are many similarities but markdown is more ubiquitous. Hugo, when joined with github and a static site service provider like render, makes updating a breeze. Just push!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I am not really a conversationalist. Here is the site, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
