<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Garys Docs – Fragments</title>
    <link>/blog/thoughts/fragments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fragments on Garys Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:05:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/blog/thoughts/fragments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Habits 01</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/28/habits-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/28/habits-01/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;It is important to practice good habits of the mind at all times. Why? When we are not actively practicing good habits, we may lazily fall into bad habits. Bad habits are formed of the aggregate of our lives mixed with the cement of our passions, heavily reinforced by repetition, and cured over long periods of time. Our bad habits are very hard to break, requiring the sturdy spike of iron will and regular strikes with the heavy hammer of our effort. They take time to form and time to break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing the ease in which bad habits take hold, we should be generous to ourselves and to others struggling with the load of their accumulated habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good habits are also strong and will support us in the most difficult of endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Composed while lawn mowing. Shouts out to CBU: Amr, Viral, and Brian)&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Grandmother Porth</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/26/grandmother-porth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/26/grandmother-porth/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Grandma Porth taught me cards and other games. While I don&amp;rsquo;t really play many games now, the lessons of probability I learned from her teaching have remained. She was a world traveler who loved new experiences and cultures. Her dedication to community service and the well-being of all those around her set an excellent example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, she seemed the iron lady but I spent many, many hours with her and the ironess was only displayed when needed. I am glad that she mostly missed my lost years but wish she could she who I have become because I think she played a significant role in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(this is likely the hardest of these for me to write)&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 410px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/blog/2020/06/26/grandmother-porth/lucile-porth_hu765997cc9d57fffd0e7f73e8f09e9a6b_478126_400x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;671&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
Lucile Porth on a travel.
&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Truth 01</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/23/truth-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/23/truth-01/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Truth is hard and I will likely give it many fragments. I consider the discernment of truth, one of the most difficult and important things to put the efforts of my mind toward. It is a goal of religions, sciences, and philosophies.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Truth 02</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/23/truth-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/23/truth-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Absolute Truth can never be known, even if such a thing were to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Gary Dalton Jr</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/21/gary-dalton-jr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/21/gary-dalton-jr/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;My Dad, Gary Dalton Jr. He struggled to find his identity and eventually paid the price for that struggle. From him, I learned the value of being open to the thoughts, ideas, opinions, and identities of others. He acknowledged to me that I do not have to think or believe others choices are correct but that I also do not have the right to use force to bring them to my idea of the correct. He demonstrated that good things may be accomplished by being oneself. He gave meticulous attention to detail and always was doing the best he could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People enjoyed his company because he was interested in them, playful, and engaging without out being ponderously opinionated. He cared greatly about his health and athleticism and I consider him one of the original health food nuts. One particular habit I have gained from him, is doing stretches and exercises while in the living room with family and watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 410px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/blog/2020/06/21/gary-dalton-jr/garydaltonjr_hu1acdb48bd4dc9afa1f9c5e6ebe76219e_30628_400x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;516&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
Gary Dalton Jr
&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Grandfather Dalton</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/19/grandfather-dalton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:05:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/19/grandfather-dalton/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Thank you to my Grandfather Dalton, the original Garold. I gained much from your enjoyment, thought, and discussion (not argument) given to politics and your great ability to care little for labels. I recall a discussion we had regarding some political subject and, in frustration, I stated that you sounded like a communist. You calmly replied that I could call it whatever I wished but your ideas would stand on their own. You also demonstrated how to live a fulfilling life of labor and that this was a noble path.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
